http://www.mtsac.edu/it/infosecurity/privacy.html

Ask Joe
Alert: Mt. SAC has Transitioned to Online Classes and Services (see www.mtsac.edu/online). Learn more about our COVID-19 response at www.mtsac.edu/health.LEARN MORE
Information Technology
Menu
About Us
Academic Technology & Infrastructure
Enterprise Application Systems
IT Advisory Committee
Organizational Structure
Information Security
Mail Services (Fiscal Services)
Mobile Devices
Online Forms
Print Services (Fiscal Services)
The purpose of this document is to describe the information collected by Mt. San Antonio
College and the use thereof.
2.0 Information Collected
Mt. San Antonio College collects personal information, including but not limited to;
name, address, email address, telephone number, social security number and educational
background. Such personal information may be requested for research, public service,
or for administrative purposes. Additional personal information, such as credit card
account information, may be requested for purchases or enrollment purposes.
3.0 Access to Educational Records
Following is a summary of the Mt. San Antonio College position related to the Family
Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974, O.L. 93-380, and Chapter 1297, Statues
of 1976, State of California:
All former and present students have the right to review and inspect their educational
records in the Office of Admissions and Records provided they make a written request
fifteen (15) days in advance. Such a review will be under the direct supervision of
a classified or certificated employee in the Admissions and Records Office. Expressly
exempted from the right of review and inspection are the following materials:
Financial records of the parents or legal guardians of the student(s
Confidential letters and statements of recommendation maintained by the College on
or before January 1, 1975, provided that such letters or statements are not used for
purposes others than those for which they were specifically intended.
Records of instructional, supervisory, counseling, and administrative personnel which
are in the sole possession of such personnel and are not accessible or revealed to
any other person except a substitute.
Records of employees of Mt. San Antonio College, made and maintained in the normal
course of business which relate exclusively to such person in that person's capacity
as an employee, are not available for use for any other purpose.
Records of students made and maintained by the Student Health Services, the College
nurse, the College physician, and the College therapist, which are used in the treatment
of students and are not available to anyone other than persons providing such treatment.
However, such a record may be personally reviewed by a physician or other appropriate
professional of the student's choice.
4.0 Use of Collected Information
Mt. San Antonio College collects and uses information necessary to administer College
business and to meet federal and state reporting requirements. The College may use
personal information collected from websites, College applications, etc. for the purpose
of future communications back to enrollees, in order to keep current and former students
informed of such activities as campus programs, symposia and or special events. Email
address may be used by faculty and administrators to communicate with students.
5.0 Information Disclosure
Any release of a student's educational records, with the exception listed below, must
be with the student's written consent.
The College may release copies of or otherwise divulge material in the student's educational
records only to the official agencies, groups, officials, or individuals specifically
mentioned below:
College staff members; provided that such employees have a legitimate educational
interest to inspect such a record
Representatives of the Comptroller General of the United States, the Secretary of
Education, an administrative head of an educational agency, state education officials,
and the United States Office of Civil Rights, where such information is necessary
to audit a program.
Accrediting organizations in order to carry out their accrediting functions.
Organizations conducting studies on behalf of the institution.
Officials of other schools or school systems in which the student seeks or intends
to enroll subject to the rights of students.
Agencies or organizations in connection with a student's application for financial
aid.
Organizations conducting studies for, or on behalf of, educational agencies or institutions
for the purpose of developing, validating, and administering predictive tests, administrating
student aid programs, and improving instruction, if such studies are conducted in
such a manner as will not permit the personal identification of students or their
parents by persons other than representatives of such organizations and such information
will be destroyed when no longer needed for the purpose for which it is compiled.
Appropriate persons in connection with an emergency if the knowledge of such information
is necessary to protect the health and safety of the student or other persons.
Courts or other agencies in compliance with a subpoena or judicial order. A reasonable
effort will be made to notify the student in advance of the compliance by the College.
6.0 Individual Choice
"Directory Information" means a student's name, email address, community of residence,
major field of study, participation in officially recognized activities and sports,
weight and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance, degrees and awards
received, and the most recent previous public or private school attended by the student.
Any student desiring to withhold "Directory Information" may file a written request
with the Director, Admissions and Records, within fifteen (15) days of the opening
day of each semester or session that the student does not want such information released.
The College reserves the right to limit or deny the release of specific categories
of directory information based upon a determination of the best interests of the student(s).
Educational records or personal information transferred to other institutions or agencies
will not be transferred to a third party without the written consent of the student.
7.0 Reporting Improper Use and Violations
Improper use and suspected violations of this document should be reported to Information
and Educational Technology via e-mail at abuse@mtsac.edu. This email list includes
representatives from Human Resources, Information and Educational Technology, the
Student Life Office, the Public Information Office, and the the Department of Police
and Campus Safety Office. Violations can also be reported via telephone to the IET
Help Desk at (909) 594-5611 ext. 4357. Report immediate threats to:
